{"id":"2018_5","name":"","memoryVerse":"\"Not one of all the Lord's good promises to Israel failed; every one was fulfilled.\" â€“ Joshua 21:45","dayQuestions":{"one":{"title":"FIRST DAY: Read the notes and the references.","questions":[{"id":"2018_5_1","questionText":"1. Use this space to record how you have seen God's activity during the week. (How has He provided, answered, comforted, reconciled, guided, etc.?)","answer":"","quotes":[]},{"id":"2018_5_2","questionText":"2. What from the notes, lecture, group sharing or personal study impacted you most in the past week?","answer":"","quotes":[]}]},"two":{"title":"SECOND DAY: Read Joshua 22.\nJoshua 22 gives the account of the tribes of Reuben, Gad and half-tribe of Manasseh returning to their land east of\nthe Jordan River. The separation caused by the river caused some difficulties and fears for the 12 tribes.","readVerse":[{"book":"Joshua","verse":"22:1-999"}],"questions":[{"id":"2018_5_3","questionText":"3. How did Joshua commend and challenge the eastern tribes? (See Joshua 22:1-8.)","answer":"","quotes":[{"book":"Joshua","verse":"22:1-8"}]},{"id":"2018_5_4","questionText":"4. What did the western tribes fear after the eastern tribes built the altar? How did the eastern tribes defend their motives in building the altar? (For help, see Deuteronomy 12:10-14.)","answer":"","quotes":[{"book":"Deuteronomy","verse":"12:10-14"}]},{"id":"2018_5_5","questionText":"5. What does this encounter teach you about dealing with confrontation in a God-honoring manner?","answer":"","quotes":[]}]},"three":{"title":"THIRD DAY: Read Joshua 23.\nJoshua 23 warns the Israelite leaders to remain devoted and obedient to the Lord.","readVerse":[{"book":"Joshua","verse":"23:1-999"}],"questions":[{"id":"2018_5_6","questionText":"6. What did Joshua want the Israelites to recognize and remember about God?","answer":"","quotes":[]},{"id":"2018_5_7","questionText":"7. What truths about God can we learn from all He did for Israel?","answer":"","quotes":[]},{"id":"2018_5_8","questionText":"8. How did Joshua instruct Israel? What was the danger for Israel should they choose to disobey?","answer":"","quotes":[]},{"id":"2018_5_9","questionText":"9. Why would Joshua address the leaders separately? What does this teach you about the need for and value of godly leadership?","answer":"","quotes":[]}]},"four":{"title":"FOURTH DAY: Read Joshua 24:1-13.\nJoshua 24 records Joshua's final reminders and warnings to the nation of Israel.","readVerse":[{"book":"Joshua","verse":"24:1-13"}],"questions":[{"id":"2018_5_10","questionText":"10. What stands out to you in reading Israel's history, and why?","answer":"","quotes":[]},{"id":"2018_5_11","questionText":"11. What does the retelling of Israel's history reveal about God?","answer":"","quotes":[]},{"id":"2018_5_12","questionText":"12. Why is it important to read, tell and hear stories of God's past faithfulness? How do you or could you put that into practice?","answer":"","quotes":[]}]},"five":{"title":"FIFTH DAY: Read Joshua 24:14-33.","readVerse":[{"book":"Joshua","verse":"24:14-33"}],"questions":[{"id":"2018_5_13","questionText":"13. What choice did Joshua present to the nation? How do we make choices everyday about whom we will serve?","answer":"","quotes":[]},{"id":"2018_5_14","questionText":"14. Why do you think Joshua did not readily accept their pledge to serve the Lord in verse 18? What lessons do you learn from Joshua's example?","answer":"","quotes":[]},{"id":"2018_5_15","questionText":"15. What did Joshua mean by God's jealousy in 24:19? What examples can you think of where jealousy is an appropriate response? (See 2 Corinthians 11:2-4.)","answer":"","quotes":[{"book":"2 Corinthians","verse":"11:2-4"}]}]},"six":{"title":"SIXTH DAY: Review Joshua 22-24.","readVerse":[{"book":"Joshua","verse":"22:1-24:999"}],"questions":[{"id":"2018_5_16","questionText":"16. What would you like to see God do in your heart or in your life this week? People of the Promised Land I Lesson 5 \" www.bsfinternational.org AdQ (06.2018) \" 7 8 \" AdQ (06.2018) www.bsfinternational.org \" People of the Promised Land I Lesson 5","answer":"","quotes":[]}]}}}